<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The case of the Company of Distillers of London, in reference to a bill, intituled, A bill for incouraging the distilling of brandy from corn, and for laying several duties upon low wines. Which bill will in reality prevent the distilling of brandy from corn, diminish the Kings revenue, and ruin the trade of distilling in England, and set up the same in foreign parts.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1690</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 5 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2013-12">2013-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B01898</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing C1047</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R227999</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">52211942</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 52211942</idno>
            <idno type="VID">175510</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B01898)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 175510)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English Books, 1641-1700 ; 2739:20)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The case of the Company of Distillers of London, in reference to a bill, intituled, A bill for incouraging the distilling of brandy from corn, and for laying several duties upon low wines. Which bill will in reality prevent the distilling of brandy from corn, diminish the Kings revenue, and ruin the trade of distilling in England, and set up the same in foreign parts.</title>
                  <author>Company of Distillers of London.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.)   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1690]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Publication data suggested by Wing.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the Lincoln's Inn Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Distilling industries --  Law and legislation --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Alcoholic beverages --  Taxation --  Law and legislation --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Broadsides --  England --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2012-06</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-07</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-09</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-09</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-02</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:175510:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>The <hi>CASE</hi> of the Company of <hi>DISTILLERS</hi> of <hi>London,</hi> in reference to a Bill, Intituled, A Bill for incourag<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the Diſtilling of Brandy from Corn, and for laying ſeveral Duties upon <hi>Low Wines.</hi>
            </head>
            <head type="sub">Which Bill will in Reality prevent the Diſtilling of <hi>Brandy</hi> from <hi>Corn,</hi> Diminiſh the Kings Revenue, and Ruin the Trade of <hi>Diſtilling</hi> in <hi>England,</hi> and ſet up the ſame in Foreign Parts.</head>
            <p>THIS Bill ſeems to be deſigned for the Conſumption of Corn, and by the Title it is intimated, as if it were intended for encreaſing Their Maje<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſties Revenue, whereas in Truth it will hinder the Conſumption of Corn, as well as leſſen the Revenue, and will be of advantage to no Perſon in <hi>England,</hi> ſave ſuch as are Importers of <hi>French</hi> Brandy, of which Brandy there is now in <hi>London</hi> about 4000 Peeces; and if a great Duty be laid on the Materials which the Diſtillers uſe for making <hi>Engliſh Brandy,</hi> they will in effect be prohibited the uſe of ſuch Materials, And the price of <hi>Brandy</hi> which is already advanced from 30 <hi>l.</hi> to 60 <hi>l.</hi> a Tun will riſe much higher.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Note,</hi> That <hi>French Brandy</hi> is now but 8 <hi>l.</hi> a Ton in <hi>France,</hi> and if the Impoſition by this Bill deſigned, be laid on the Materials now uſed in <hi>England,</hi> 'twill make <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>he <hi>French</hi> Traders run all manner of Hazards to bring in <hi>French Brandy</hi> for ſo v<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ſ<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> a Profit, and no Induſtry or Integrity of the Officers will be able to keep it out.</p>
            <p>Spirits or <hi>Brandy</hi> made from Corn is not ſo palateable or grateful to the Sto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mach as <hi>Brandy</hi> made from <hi>Moloſſes</hi> or <hi>Sugar,</hi> whereas <hi>Brandy</hi> made from <hi>Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>laſſes</hi> or <hi>Sugar</hi> almoſt equals Foreign <hi>Brandy,</hi> and conſequently brings down the Price of it; and by the Diſtillers Skill in mingling <hi>Brandy</hi> made from <hi>Moloſſes</hi> with Spirits made from Corn, they have occaſioned the ſale and conſumption in Kind of ſeveral thouſand Ton of <hi>Brandy</hi> made from Corn which otherwiſe could not have been conſumed in kind, and therefore the Importers of Foreign <hi>Brandy</hi> have uſed all Induſtry to prohibit the <hi>Diſtillers</hi> the uſe of <hi>Moloſſes,</hi> and if this Bill paſs 8 <hi>d.</hi> a Gallon is thereby intended to be laid on Low Wines extracted from <hi>Moloſſes,</hi> which with the Duty already thereon will amount to 23 <hi>l.</hi> a Ton upon the Spirit, which is ſo great a Duty that the <hi>Distillers</hi> cannot uſe it, and then the Importers of Foreign <hi>Brandy</hi> have their Ends, but Their Majeſties and the Nation will be injured for that the Revenue and the conſumption of Malted Corn will thereby be leſſened.</p>
            <p>The <hi>Diſtillers</hi> do now uſe many Thouſand Quarters of Corn in a Year, and do make as good <hi>Brandy</hi> from Corn as can be made by any Perſon whatſoever, and if they had incouragement could make much greater quantities than can be con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſumed here and in Foreign Parts, yet this Bill layes open the Trade to every un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>skilful pretender; which will put Their Majeſties to much greater Expence in Col<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lecting the Duty and incourage the making a bad Commodity for the makers pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fit, who are under no regulation or puniſhment if they ſo do. The Conſequence whereof will be the preventing the conſumption of Corn, and ruin the <hi>Diſtillers,</hi> whoſe Company firſt invented the making of <hi>Spirits</hi> from Corn, and who for theſe many years paſt have born a proportionable part of the Expence neceſſary for the ſupport of the Honour and Government of the City, and are now increaſed with their Apprentices and Servants to be very numerous.</p>
            <p>The Duty laid on Spirits made from <hi>Molloſſes</hi> by this Bill is ſo great that it can<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>not be uſed here, therefore the Merchants will be forced to ſend their <hi>Molloſſes</hi> to <hi>Holland,</hi> where it is made partly into Sugar by Refiners and Sugar-Bakers, and partly Diſtilled; and both thoſe Trades were till lately either not known, or rarely practiced there, but are ſince grown conſiderable; and if this Bill paſſes, will both be much advanced, and the <hi>Dutch</hi> will not only in Foreign parts under-ſell us, but by Veſſels laid near our Harbors for that purpoſe, ſupply all our Outward<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bound Ships with the Spirits made of <hi>Molloſſes</hi> as cheap or cheaper than we can with Spirits made of Corn, <hi>tho' that be much worſe than what is made of Molaſſes,</hi> becauſe we pay a great Duty and they none.</p>
            <p>There are ſeveral other parts of this Bill which tend not only to the Deſtruction of the <hi>Diſtillers</hi> Trade, but of Their Majeſties Plantations, and the leſſening Their Majeſties Revenue, and will promote the Intereſt of Foreigners, and other Miſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chiefs which the <hi>Diſtillers</hi> are ready to make appear if they may be permitted to be heard thereunto.</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:175510:2"/>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
